so the trust certificate
and the certificate of trust is the same thing let's
clarify and clear any confusion there
but in regards to the trust certificate I still hear people going
to the bank to open a trust account
now all of this ties in walk with me there's a two types of
facilities that is offered to trust at banks they they offer
trust accounts then they offer trust bank accounts
but if you go open a trust bank account it's wrapped up in public
registrations
and if you're doing deposits same thing it's wrapped up in public
regulations
so uh if you have a trust certificate
and you open a trust account
the only thing you left with is making a deposit
so you got to put money in it out of your pocket or either
this is why people be stuck on trying to deposit the birth certificate
because actually they set up something for public regulations
and trying to do a private process
so the funds that's in the
account is not the money obviously trust funds
is like interest and securities
collateral assets and things like that
now the difference in a trust account and a trust bank account is
the trust bank account is the one that we just explained
and then the trust account
is the kind of account that holds the estate
when you done the private banking transaction
of transferring rights title and interest
from your estate to your trust
your life estate to your trust
that transaction needs to be held somewhere
and all of those transactions are recorded
and the trust certificate now
represents the identity of the trust
and identity of the trustee
and it is a receipt of that transaction
so when I'm give my trust certificate to a banker at a bank
I'm not opening a bank account I'm submitting my trust certificate
for future obligations
debts and to cover the benefit of the beneficiaries
so I don't understand um how we still have
a misunderstanding between
what's going on with the trust account
versus the trust bank account
and this discrepancy between
the trust certificate or certificate of trust
all of this is established through the life estate planning model
and um if you want a walkthrough on how this goes
come take a walk with me so in less than three minutes
I'll explain to you how a person would even have a reason to deposit
bills or end up settling if you are
the settler
in the trust atmosphere or the trust ecosystem that you have
you should be settling all accounts
hence the word settler but these are just simple terms that are
are actually transformed into being action items we breathe
life into those through the life estate so in three minutes
I'll just explain to you the difference between the trust
rabbit hole that you've been going down to
go with your trust certificate and open a trust account
and then we also have to make mention of the beneficiaries
there's a misunderstanding there as well
the beneficiary is there to benefit
commonly the beneficiary doesn't have a voice in the matter
because the beneficiary benefits from what was established for them
in the event that the beneficiary see that there's a fiduciary breach
that a trustee is doing then the beneficiary can step up for that
outside of that beneficiaries only benefit
I think we're confusing the beneficiary with beneficial owner
and the full statement is principal and beneficial owner
and the beneficial owner is the one who has equitable interest
principal is the one who holds title so that covers
title legal title plus equitable interest
and we're confusing the beneficiary
with the beneficial owner
so these are just a few basic
pointers and none of this is even private banking yet
this is what make you get
the salute and the respect at the banks that they see
you presenting your trust estate
life estate ecosystem properly
so you have a reason to go into private banking
so that was the second portion
in total this was less than five minutes of edification
if um anybody want to
have these type of particulars exchanged with you intricate details
about what we're already doing and execute and actually have
results from what you have tap in let's get busy